<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HUNgarian ⇄ GERman</title>
    <link>https://hunger.dpat.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HUNgarian ⇄ GERman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 13:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hunger.dpat.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>002 — Érdeklődjön szállás után egy utazási irodában!</title>
      <link>https://hunger.dpat.in/posts/002-room-reservation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 13:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hunger.dpat.in/posts/002-room-reservation/</guid>
      <description>a) Jó napot kívánok!
Guten Tag!

Három napot szeretnék a Balatonnál tölteni.
Ich möchte drei Tage am Balaton verbringen.

Milyen szálláslehetőségeik vannak?
Bitte, was für Unterkunftsmöglichkeiten haben Sie da?

Vagy szállodában vagy fizetővendég-szobában tudjuk elhelyezni.
Wir können Sie entweder im Hotel oder in einem Privatzimmer unterbringen.

A fizetővendég-szoba olcsóbb.
Das Privatzimmer ist natürlich billiger.

Az utóbbit választanám, ha van a szobához fürdőszoba, és ha a ház nincs túl messze a vízparttól.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>001 — Kérdezze meg a szálloda portását, hogy juthat el legkönnyebben a repülőtérre!</title>
      <link>https://hunger.dpat.in/posts/001-easiest-way-to-airport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hunger.dpat.in/posts/001-easiest-way-to-airport/</guid>
      <description>Délután négy órára kint kell lennem a repülőtéren.
Um vier Uhr nachmittags muss ich am Flughafen sein.
I have to be at the airport at four in the afternoon.
Kérem, mondja meg, hogyan jutok el a legkönnyebben oda?
Sagen Sie mir, bitte, wie ich am einfachsten hinkomme.
Please tell me how I can get there the easiest.
A közvetlen repülőtéri járatok az utazási iroda előtt állnak.
Die Zubringerbusse stehen vor dem Reisebüro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is It All About</title>
      <link>https://hunger.dpat.in/posts/000-what-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 23:59:59 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hunger.dpat.in/posts/000-what-is-it/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
Half a month ago I was in one book shop in Budapest where I bought an amazing book. The book that can finally satisfy my curiosity in both Hungarian and German languages. It&#39;s named “Hogy mondjunk németül?“ (~ “How to speak German?“).
What I&#39;m going to do is to publish bilingual texts from the book few times a week, giving simultaneously an English translation, too. There&#39;re in general 290 entries so it should be done the way that by the end of the year all the entries are considered.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>